what's up everybody phil blackman with
barbadon.com and today we are going to
cover the 2021 rogue invitational
individual and legends crossfit
competitions if you want to learn
anything about what's going to go down
at the dell diamond stadium in round
rock texas over the weekend in the rogue
invitational just head over to google
type in bar bend rogue invitational and
all of our coverage is going to come up
you're not going to want to miss out
it's going to be an epic show the 2021
rogue invitational is taking place on
october 29th through the 31st in round
rock texas and will be streamed live on
the rogue fitness youtube channel two
main features include the individual
crossfit competition and the legends
crossfit competition two-time rogue
invitational women's champion tia claire
toomey orr and the 2020 world
invitational men's champion pat velner
will be on hand to defend their titles
both athletes are part of a field of 20
women and 20 men composed of the top 21
crossfit games finishers including five
of the six podium individuals the
athletes will be competing for a
record-breaking prize purse only topped
by the crossfit games themselves the
legends competition likewise will see 16
crossfit icons nine men and seven women
who were top contenders and fan
favorites in the early years of the
games the rogue invitational brings
together crossfit's past and present
stars who make up a significant amount
of the sport's history here's who you
should keep your eyes on in the
individual division of course five-time
reigning crossfit games champion tia
claire toomey or she's vying for her
third straight rogue invitational title
in addition to prepping for the rogue
invitational to me or has been busy
training to qualify for the 2022 winter
olympics on the australian bobsled team
shortly after winning her fifth straight
games title last august the australian
was at the new york lake placid bobsled
training center prepping for the
upcoming bobsled season incredible stuff
from toomey or being able to train for
both crossfit and bobsled simultaneously
and still putting up major results let's
chat about justin medeiros how does the
freshly minted fittest man on earth
perform in his first competition after
winning the games the 2021 games were
only maderos's second career competition
victory he won the 2019 filthy 150 to
qualify for the 2020 crossfit games it's
hard to say if medeiros will go on a
winning streak as many other champions
have done as he faces stiff competition
at the rogue invitational and in the
next game season including pat valencia
bkg and saxon panchik let's talk about
pat valner the returning rogue
invitational champion he's also coming
off a second silver medal finish at the
crossfit games and fourth overall games
podium finish of his career after a few
stumbles at the 2019 and 2020 crossfit
games velner is back in top form a
second rogue invitational championship
will be a great way to cap off vilner's
year and build momentum for a run at the
coveted title of fittest man on earth in
2022 other notable individuals to look
out for carrie pierce had to withdraw
right before the start of the crossfit
games due to having covet 19.
additionally she announced that the
rogue invitational would be her last
crossfit competition before she retires
let's talk about sam quant he had a long
time chronic illness flare-up right
before the 2021 mid-atlantic crossfit
challenge which hindered his performance
leaving him in 14th place however he did
play second at the 2020 games
insinuating that he could do well at the
rogue invitational moving over into the
legends competitions there is a mix of
actively competing legends and ones that
have moved on from competitive crossfit
rich froning and dan bailey are still
competing in the games seasons as are
annie sakamoto and rebecca voigt miller
for the women frowning jumped into the
legends competition for the amanda event
in 2019 but this will be his first full
legends competition and it's tough to
say he's not the favorite to win as a
four-time fittest man on earth he's the
only athlete to rank in the top 19
worldwide in every open there are a
total of nine individuals that will be
competing in their third invitational
tia claire to me or catherine david's
daughter ben smith sam briggs pat
fellner laura horvath kristen holter
cole sager and chandler smith conversely
there will be several rogue invitational
rookies this year both in the individual
and legends competition a total of nine
men and 12 women the most notable are
josh bridges justin medeiros mal o'brien
and emma carey o'brien and carrie both
17 years old are coming off stellar 2021
crossfit games performances and will
look to continue their upper
trajectories at the rogue invitational
with a seventh place games finisher
o'brien and a 16th place finish for
kerry the rest of the women's field must
contend with these future games
powerhouses how much have they improved
in the three months since the 2021
crossfit games the invitational is sure
to let us know as the first year of the
new crossfit games offseason schedule
winds down the rogue invitational is a
can't miss occurrence the rogue
invitational is sure to bring out the
best form of all of these athletes in
both competition and camaraderie and
fans will get to enjoy the spectacle
along the way we at bar bend surely will
we hope you will too until then i'm phil
blackman for barban.com thanks for
watching
[Music]
[Laughter]
you